# RAHEEM, SEGUN IBRAHIM

E-Mail: <a href="mailto:segunibrahim2019@gmail.com">segunibrahim2019@gmail.com</a>

Phone: +2348070837632, +2348160394614

Address: Behind YAWUNDE GUEST INN Tumfure Gombe, Gombe State.

## **SUMMARY**

I am a seasoned Medical Laboratory Scientist with over three years of experience in Microbiology, Chemical Pathology, Histopathology and Hematology testing needs. I am hardworking and ready to take ownership of the laboratory's diagnostic performance and safety records. I am dedicated to providing rapid turnaround time without sacrificing personnel safety or diagnostic accuracy. I am keen on adopting emerging laboratory techniques and advanced diagnostic technologies. I am skilled at multitasking with excellent communication and problem solving skills. I have a proven history of maintaining equipment and strict adherence with prescribed safety protocols and regulatory guidelines for laboratory operations and subject privacy.

### **OBJECTIVE**

Learning to acquire the knowledge, skills, professional attitude and ability necessary to accurately and proficiently perform in any field I find myself.

## **EDUCATION**

Qualification	Year Obtained	Institution Attended
Bachelor of Medical Laboratory Science (BMLS)	2017	Ambrose Alli University, Ekpoma, Edo State.
West African Senior School Certificate (SSCE)	2009	Zanna Royal Academy, Ekpoma, Edo State.
First Leaving School Certificates (Nursery and Primary)	2003	Mousco Nursery And Primary School, Ekpoma, Edo State.

# **OTHER CERTIFICATES**

- Microsoft office suite, 2006.
- Planning for Monitoring and Evaluation, 2019.

# **WORK HISTORY**

• ORGANIZATION: Muskash Medical Diagnostic Center, Edo State.

**POSITION:** Medical laboratory Scientist

**DURATION:** June, 2017 to November, 2018

### **RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Oversaw shipment and reception of laboratory specimens, verifying proper safety precautions and handling methods.
- Analyzed body fluids in accordance with standard operating procedures.
- Utilized expertise in Microbiology, Chemical Pathology and Hematology to help in diagnosis of medical issues.
- Operated Spectrophotometer, Compound microscope etc., maintaining strict adherence to prescribed safety guidelines and operational instructions.
- Documented test results using computerized and manual methods.
- Identified and resolved unexpected results, directing secondary testing measures or collection efforts.
- Kept laboratory equipment clean and in good working condition for optimal functionality and longevity.
- Led quality control diagnostic testing, documenting all variances in results and blood product performance.
- Trained and oversaw the development of laboratory assistants.

• **ORGANIZATION:** Federal Teaching Hospital (FTH), Gombe.

**POSITION:** Medical laboratory Scientist

**DURATION:** January, 2019 to February, 2021

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Analyzed body fluids and tissue in accordance with standard operating procedures.
- Utilized expertise in Microbiology, Chemical Pathology, Histopathology, Hematology and PCR techniques to help in diagnosis of medical issues.
- Analyzed testing results based on established indicators and submitting findings to central lab database.
- Operated Automated Enzyme Immunoassay Analyzer (AIA-360), Rayto Chemray 240
  Autoanalyzer, Rayto Eliser Reader (RT-2100C), Pima CD4 analyzer, Rayto Hemaray 51 etc,
  maintaining strict adherence to prescribed safety guidelines and operational instructions.
- Performed and documented accurate transfusion reaction investigations.
- Documented test results using computerized and manual methods.
- Identified and resolved unexpected results, directing secondary testing measures or collection efforts.
- Kept laboratory equipment clean and in good working condition for optimal functionality and longevity.
- **ORGANIZATION:** Nigerian Centre for Disease Control

**POSITION:** Medical Scientist at the NYSC Orientation Camp Gombe.

DURATION: November, 2020 to February, 2021

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Educated the people and prospective corp members on the common symptoms associated with the corona virus as well as the procedures for testing.
- Collected nasopharyngeal and orophareangeal samples for Rapid Diagnostic Test and PCR analysis.
- Collated the results of the findings and take appropriate actions based on the results.

## **SKILLS**

- Specimen Collection and Processing.
- Documentation skills.
- Laboratory procedures and test analysis.
- Equipment calibration, Operation and Monitoring.
- Safety regulations and Exposure control plans.
- Quality Control.
- Good interpersonal relationship skills with the ability to work effectively in a team.
- Hardworking with leadership-qualities.
- Time Management.

**REFEREE:** Available on request.